I've been experiencing very dry skin
lately. Could this be a side effect of
TRT? My dosage is um 200 milligrams
twice a week. That's nothing uh we hear
very often because uh normally we we
hear of uh more oily skin.
>> Sure. Sure. Yeah. I'm usually telling
guys how to Yeah. Let's teach you how to
just get you to dry up those uh you know
sebaceous glands a little bit with some
you know some zinc or some B5 or you
know that kind of stuff or some you know
some uh some topical shampoo as body
wash to to dry you out instead of being
dry. Yes. So I I doubt it. I doubt
that's what's that's what's going on
there. Um you know and we just talked a
little bit about thyroid. I would check
out your thyroid though too. I see a lot
of skin issues with with some thyroid. I
would I would want to see what your what
your numbers look like there, you know,
beyond just the TSH to see what a free,
you know, a free T3 looks like and see
how see how that's going. Um, take a
good look at your diet, too. Um, I see a
lot of guys, uh, maybe you maybe you
noticed this, too. Uh, we're pretty
deficient in essential fatty acids.
>> Yeah.
>> Not a lot of guys are eating fatty fish
three, four times a week to get enough
of that kind of thing. So, sometimes
substituting with some fish oil can go
go a real long way. It depends upon your
environment here too, right? I'm here in
Phoenix in the desert. We see people
running pretty, you know, pretty dry on
top of all of it. So, staying well
hydrated, keeping an eye on your
essential fatty acids. I think those are
all important things. Take a look at
your thyroid. I I don't think it's the
testosterone doing that though.
>> But one should accept getting older. The
sky be the skin becomes drier anyway
[clears throat] in everyone. And
especially I always tell my patients, it
goes from bottom up. Uh it starts with
your feet, your legs. Everything is just
getting drier. So you just make it a
habit putting on a little bit of Yeah.
body cream hydration every day after the
shower.
>> Yeah. You start getting flakier and
flakier, right? You take off your socks
and there's a
>> plume of uh
>> plume of skin cells floating around.
Yeah.
>> That's what I see in my practice every
day, Mike. They
>> got to hold your breath. Don't inhale
that.
>> Older guys or women 80 years, they take
off their their pants and it's snowing
everywhere. So
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> You know,
>> just getting older. So,